<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kkol</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on kkol</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Secrets</title>
      <link>/posts/secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/secrets/</guid>
      <description>No more hidden secrets. Not only Vault is used for storing secrets. You can keep them right in your Rancher environment. Though, if you may easily view values in Vault, in Rancher you have to know where to look for.
You can list your secrets, and view a particular one in API. That&amp;rsquo;s what I did, and saw: value: null
Still, I was sure the secret had been set. Thanks to the following article, the solution was found: Go to the container&amp;rsquo;s shell, and</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim</title>
      <link>/posts/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/vim/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s hard to quit using it. But just for the first time. After notepad++ on Windows, linux terminal text editors look unusual. Nano is just simple with prompts, otherwise vim is hard to handle. First time I opened vim, I had to close terminal itself, because I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize how to quit. I watched some Sander van Vugt&amp;rsquo;s explanations on using vim, before I returned to it. And finally weeks later I revealed vim tutor, which is definitely a firm first step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there My name is Konstantin and welcome to my personal blog!
I&amp;rsquo;m glad to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve started my fabulous DevOps path and I solemnly swear to share all useful knowledge I get on the way.
For now, I&amp;rsquo;m learning Linux (RHCSA), networking (CCNA) and python. Basic stuff goes first, but I plan to gradually complicate articles (as I learn new). Hope this blog will be usuful for all of us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
